JAMES CUTLER

6 Central Ave, Kittery ME · 617-960-7635

jcutler@HubSpot.com

https://github.com/jcutlah | https://jamespcutler.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamespcutler/

A proven contributor with experience developing on the HubSpot CMS. A process-oriented professional, with a technical track record, high aptitude for learning, and the ability to quickly respond to feedback. Enjoys technical challenges as well as mentoring colleagues on his team and throughout the organization. In all roles, has focused on developing on the HubSpot CMS. Currently enrolled in the UNH Coding Bootcamp to further his technical skillset.

EXPERIENCE

WEBSITE TECHNICAL CONSULTANT, HUBSPOT

OCT 2017 - PRESENT

- Managed website migration and template setup processes in an internal-/external-facing capacity.
- Trained customers of varying technical aptitudes on how to use the HubSpot CMS tools.
- Deployed several Python applications to automate team processes in key areas.
- Consistently applied an understanding of DNS/web servers in helping customers go live on HubSpot.
- Actively contributed to a repository of modules and snippets used by migration technicians.
- Mentored teammates in technical areas including HubL, HubDB, and JavaScript.

DESIGNATED SUPPORT ENGINEER, HUBSPOT

JUL 2016 - OCT 2017

- Solved and consulted on technical implementation issues in a variety of environments: HubSpot tools, the Salesforce connector, and third party/custom database integrations.
- Built a paginated/filterable HubDB solutions repository that served as a resource to teammates.
- Developed Python/REST API scripts to solve for unique customer use-cases.
- Created a disengaged customer playbook, protecting MRR through proactive customer engagement.

SUPPORT ENGINEER, HUBSPOT

OCT 2015 - JUL 2016

- 3000+ cases solved in 9 months with an overall average NPS above 90%.
- Recognized by Product Experts as a valuable resource to colleagues in the CMS-related Support Slack channels.

SKILLS

- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript (vanilla and jQuery)
- HubL and HubDB
- Responsive Design
- Integrations and REST APIs

- Python
- Domain Name Systems/go-live process
- Git/GitHub
- Chrome Developer tools
- Google App Engine

CONTRIBUTIONS

- Developed a module for managing a multi-lingual blog in HubSpot, and posted a tutorial about it on the HubSpot User Blog.
- Deployed a web crawler app, in use by the Migrations team, that regularly scans delivered website/blog migration projects to check for a website domain connection to HubSpot.
- Deployed a rotator app to automate CMS Approval/Support Ticket assignment on the migrations team.
- Deployed a custom module injector, in use by the migration technicians. This is allowing the
 migrations team to enforce code consistency and quality with our offshore technicians, while
 reducing spending on migrations.
- Deployed several apps in use by the Migrations team, which solve for product areas that do not support migrating more than one website.
- Posted to the HubSpot User Blog, showcasing an application of HubSpot CRM deal automation to solve for a project management process in Migrations.

EDUCATION

MAY 2009

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN NATURAL RESOURCE STUDIES, UNIVERSITY OF

MASSACHUSETTS AMHERST

- GPA 3.6/4.0, National Society of Leadership and Success.
- President/Lead Guide of UMASS Outing Club.
- Managed a team of 15 people.
- Purchased recreation equipment on a \$25,000 annual budget.
- Guided groups of 6-10 participants on 3-7 day backpacking trips in northern New England.

SEPTEMBER 2019

UNIVERSITY OF NEW HAMPSHIRE CODING BOOTCAMP

- Currently enrolled in the September 2019 cohort.
- Full stack web development, leveraging the MERN stack (MongoDB and MySQL, Express.js, React.js, and Node.js)
- Current academic average: A